<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about">Nairobi City is a capital of Kenya, East Africa. Its name comes from a Maasai name Enkare which means Cool waters and derived from Nairobi River which traverses through the city. It is one of the few cities in the world with a National Park close to the capital center. Nairobi is no doubt the most popular city in East Africa. It is vibrant, full of life and a host of many tours and travel destinations. Whether you are a luxury tourist or a budget backpacker, time spent in the city and its neighborhoods will create a memorable experience. Nairobi is a cosmopolitan city deriving its population from different counties in Kenya and from all over the world. Being a host of many international organizations, it hosts many expatriates. The official language in Nairobi is English but Kiswahili (National Language) is widely spoken. If it is your first time in Nairobi, Kenya, you will have a great experience of the city and nearby attractions by indulging in a full day private tour. We believe that the best way to learn your way around the city center and know about its history, people’s way of life, business activities, Nature, and landscapes is by taking a walk and interacting with the Locals.\n\n~via <b>Wander Kenya</b></string>
    <string name="maasai_market_name">Maasai Market</string>
    <string name="maasai_market_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="maasai_market_closing">1800</string>
    <string name="maasain_market_contact">0715225835</string>
    <string name="maasai_market_about">For the ultimate breath of culture and color, the Masai Market gives you the opportunity to buy authentic African art, hand- crafted beaded jewelry and clothing as souvenirs, gifts and even decorating material you could use for your home back in your country. At very affordable prices, you can purchase as many products as possible and at the same time promote local handicraft businesses.</string>
    <string name="maasai_market_location">Tuesday:Kijabe Street opposite the Norfolk Hotel \nWednesday: Capital Centre on Mombasa Road near the airport \nThursday: Nakumatt Junction Shopping Mall on Ngong Road \nFriday: Village Market in Gigiri (the upper car park) \nSaturday: The High Court parking lot in the city center (behind the Hilton) Sunday: Yaya Centre in Hurlingham</string>
    <string name="kicc_name">Kenyatta International Convention Centre</string>
    <string name="kicc_location">Harambee Avenue Nairobi</string>
    <string name="kicc_about">Kenyatta International Convention Centre (KICC) is a State Corporation established under the Tourism Act 2011 whose objective and purpose is to promote the business of Meetings, Incentives travel, Conferences and Exhibitions also known as MICE. KICC is the largest Convention centre in Eastern Africa with the capacity to hold a large number of delegates. Our largest room, The Tsavo ballroom has the capacity to host over 4000 delegates. KICC boasts of state of the art all round facilities such as simultaneous interpretation Equipment (SIE) with the capability of translating upto 7 languages, a modern business center, banking facility, Expansive grounds, ample and secure parking. The center has been revamped and refurbished over the years. The renovations at the center have seen the rebranding of meeting rooms and a large percentage of the facility to reflect the great diversity of Kenya’s tourist attractions. The center is PAD friendly with ramps that go throughout the center making it accessible to all our guests. The Kenyatta International Convention Centre has well trained and professional employees who are happy to help and give you a world class experience.</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_name">Supreme Court of Kenya</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_location">Near Kenyatta International Conference Centre, City Hall</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_about">The Supreme Court of Kenya sits at the intersection of Taifa Road and City Hall Way in the capital Nairobi. It is located in the Central Business District, next to the Kenyatta International Conference Centre (KICC), and the Office of Governor of the Nairobi County Government. The Supreme Court Building was built in 1931 and is the official seat of the Chief Justice, the Chief Registrar and the Supreme Court itself. It has played host to many high-profile visitors including Hilary Clinton, who visited in 2012 as Secretary of State, and HE Kofi Annan, who has visited several times. The building is of national heritage value by virtue of its rich history and architecture. It is classified as a national monument under the Antiquities and Monuments Act.The building has three floors and a basement. It can be accessed via two gates: the main gate on City Hall Way and the other on Taifa Road, opposite Kenya Re Plaza. Other gates for special access exist.</string>
    <string name="supreme_court_contact">020 2221221</string>
    <string name="kicc_contact">0202214535</string>
    <string name="judiciary_museum_name">The Judiciary Museum</string>
    <string name="judiciary_museum_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="judiciary_museum_Closing">1700</string>
    <string name="judiciary_museum_contact">2022212213</string>
    <string name="judiciary_museum_about">The Judiciary Museum of Kenya opened its doors to the public in June 2016. The facility located in the Eastern wing of the Supreme Court Building basement, and one of its kind in East Africa and beyond, showcases the rich history of the Judiciary. It features key documents and objects of great judicial heritage value. The museum was inspired by the need to open up the Judiciary to the public, in line with Pillar 1 of the Judiciary Transformation Framework on People-Centredness and Public Engagement.The facility will enhance public understanding and appreciation of the evolution of legal and judicial institutions in Kenya. The project was implemented in partnership with the National Museums of Kenya (NMK) over three years.</string>
    <string name="national_archives_name">Kenya National Archives</string>
    <string name="national_archives_location">Moi Ave, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="national_archives_opening">0830</string>
    <string name="national_archives_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="national_archives_contact">020 2228959</string>
    <string name="national_archives_about">Kenya National Archives and Documentation Services (KNADS) is situated at the edge of the central business district in downtown Nairobi along Moi Avenue next to Ambassadeur Hotel. The archives look out on the landmark Hilton Hotel, while on the rear side is Tom Mboya street. It was established in 1965. It holds 40,000 volumes.[4] It was established by an Act of the Parliament of Kenya in 1965 and was placed under the office of the Vice President and the Minister of Home Affairs. It is currently under the office of the Vice-President and Ministry of State for National Heritage and Culture. The Kenya National Archives building also houses the Murumbi Gallery which contains African artifacts that were collected in the 19th century.</string>
    <string name="august_7th_name">August 7th Memorial Park</string>
    <string name="august_7th_location">Junction of Moi Avenue and Haile Selassie Avenue, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="august_7th_opening">0600</string>
    <string name="august_7th_closing">1800</string>
    <string name="august_7th_contact">0722 323302</string>
    <string name="august_7th_about">The AUGUST 7TH MEMORIAL PARK also functions as a Centre of outreach to the public, to educate Kenyans on the appalling consequences of terrorism and violence and the need for peace, tolerance and reconciliation. The Memorial Park is a tribute to the innocent people who lost their lives as a result of the 1998 bombing, a tribute to the courage of those who have coped with injuries sustained and/or the loss of a loved one and a condemnation of terrorism. The Park makes a statement on the futility of terrorism and that virtues of humanity will prevail. KEY FEATURES TO BE SEEN AT MEMORIAL PARK:  The Memorial Wall: The Central Feature of the park is the wall that commemorates the 218 people who died- with each name inscribed on a granite slab. The Plants: All the plants are indigenous Kenya plants selected from different parts of the country to signify that each Kenyan was affected by the blast. The Fountain: A fountain made in the famous Ying Yang sign bubbles is in the Centre of the Park and is a symbol of life. The Mind, Body, and Spirit Sculpture: A sculpture made up of debris from the blast , dominates one side at the Park- striking and poignant at the same time. The Rocks: The rocks that align the park walk way were collected from different riverbeds all over the country to signify that each Kenyan was affected by the blast. The Memorial staff are available to give guided tours of the site as scheduled groups.</string>
    <string name="parliament_name">Kenya Parliament Buildings</string>
    <string name="parliament_location">Nairobi CBD</string>
    <string name="parliament_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="parliament_closing">1830</string>
    <string name="parliament_contact">020 2221291</string>
    <string name="parliament_about">Kenya\'s Parliament House is an iconic landmark in Nairobi with its large English-style clock tower.</string>
    <string name="uhuru_park_name">Uhuru Park</string>
    <string name="uhuru_park_location">Uhuru Highway-Kenyatta Avenue</string>
    <string name="uhuru_park_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="uhuru_park_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="uhuru_park_about">Uhuru Park is a 12.9 hectare recreational park adjacent to the central business district of Nairobi, Kenya. It was opened to the general public by the late Mzee Jomo Kenyatta on 23 May 1969. It contains an artificial lake, several national monuments, and an assembly ground which has become a popular skateboarding spot on weekends and also a location for local skateboarding competitions (best trick contest 2017), catering to Nairobi\'s growing skate scene. Apart from skateboarding, the assembly ground is used for occasional political and religious gatherings. It is infamous as the site where protest against illegal land grabbing was violently broken up by the Moi regime. In 1989, Wangari Maathai and many of her followers held a protest at the park, attempting to stop the construction of the 60-storey Kenya Times Media Trust business complex. She was forced by the government to vacate her office and was vilified in parliament, but her protests and the government\'s response led foreign investors to cancel the project. In August 1996, a group led by a Catholic cardinal and Archbishop Maurice Michael Otunga burned a heap of condoms in Uhuru Park. Uhuru Park was the scene of a bomb blast in June 2010, which killed six people and left over 100 people injured. The attack targeted a \"NO\" campaign rally for the forthcoming constitutional referendum.</string>
    <string name="city_market_name">City Market</string>
    <string name="city_market_location">Muindi Mbingu St, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="city_market_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="city_market_closing">1830</string>
    <string name="city_market_contact">0722 984538</string>
    <string name="city_market_about">It is one of the oldest formal markets in Kenya. Here, traders sell flowers, fish vegetables, handicrafts, artworks, and jewelry.</string>
    <string name="mcmillan_name">McMillan Memorial Library</string>
    <string name="mcmillan_location">Banda Street, next to Jamia Mosque</string>
    <string name="mcmillan_opening">0700</string>
    <string name="mcmillan_closing">1800</string>
    <string name="mcmillan_about">Situated along Banda Street, next to Jamia Mosque, in Nairobi, McMillan Memorial Library is arguably the oldest library in Kenya. Housed in one of the landmark buildings in Nairobi which is guarded by two masonry lions, the facility was erected and donated by Lady McMillan in memory of her husband, the US-born philanthropist Sir William Northrup McMillan. It opened its doors on June 15, 1931 in a ceremony presided by Governor Sir Joseph Byrne. At the time, the objectives and scope of the library included: The establishment, maintenance and development of a reference library; a leading library; the provision of a reading room where a supply of the latest newspapers and magazines are available; the establishment, maintenance and development of a circulating library service for the circulation of books to any point or parts of East Africa; the organisation, promotion and encouragement of the three-fold functions of libraries, namely; cultural, vocation and recreation ; and co-operation with, or contribution to, societies, corporations, trusts, or funds. During the initial stages, an estimated 500 visitors and subscribers entered the building daily to use research facilities, borrow books for home reading, view exhibition of treasures or read magazine and newspapers. With time, it expanded to stock over 200,000 items including books, reference materials, maps, slides, and reels of microfilms. The library used to open during weekdays full time, lunch hour inclusive and half-day on Saturdays. At the time annual subscription was Sh35 for borrowing one book at time within the municipality boundary of Nairobi while those outside paid Sh40. Children under 16 years, irrespective of place residence paid Sh10. The brains behind this project recognised that “the establishment of special libraries for children has been a feature of public library practice in Great Britain during the last 40 years, and this is rightly regarded as the corner stone of all library provision. These special facilities have been incorporated in the library scheme at such an early date.” The children library was dedicated in 1948 and called Mabel Rushton (to her memory) Children’s Library. In a nutshell, the library was to be developed “into a beneficial and necessary adjunct in the social and educational life of the colony.” The City Council of Nairobi took over the management of the library in 1962, and has been running it since.</string>
    <string name="central_park_name">Central Park</string>
    <string name="central_park_location">Kenyatta Avenue, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="central_park_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="central_park_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="central_park_contacts">+254 720 650869</string>
    <string name="central_park_about">Central Park is a recreational park of the city of Nairobi.Central Park is a place of rest that is located amidst all the busy life of the city of Nairobi and amidst the high-rise development at the Nairobi city centre. Central Park in Nairobi is one of the few places found within the city of Nairobi where one can run to for a picnic atmosphere. Central Park in Nairobi is located on the upper side of Nairobi city near University of Nairobi. This green reserve park in Nairobi borders Uhuru Highway, Kenyatta Avenue, Serena Hotel and Nyerere Road. Mostly, central park can be confused as an extension of the vast Uhuru Park that is its neighbour. Central park is a major destination of the city especially during lunch breaks and in the afternoons for both the locals as well as the tourists in Kenya. The tourists in Nairobi appreciate the cool environment offered in the park which is a huge contrast to environment in the middle of Nairobi town in Kenya. Central Park in Kenya has a memorial to honour the late Jomo Kenyatta, who was the first president of Kenya. The Jomo Kenyatta memorial in Central Park was elected in this park to show that Kenyans appreciate the freedom fighters who made Kenya a nation of its own. It shows that our citizens in Kenya are patriots and could protect their land any time. It is also a good way to show honour of our past leaders in Kenya. This monument on Central Park grounds in Nairobi greets you as you enter the park from Uhuru Highway. The park in city of Nairobi is often visited for its lush green wealth that offers a soothing relief from the hustle and bustle of everyday life. In other places of the city, you will find people walking fast doing their usual businesses, but in this part of town, people are usually resting under shades of the tree in the park and sitting on the grass which offers one some respite. Central Park is a haven where one escapes the scorching sun in the city of Nairobi! The rising and falling green spaces in Central Park in Nairobi city are perfect for picnics and family fun-days out. The presence of face-painters, hawkers and professional photographers in Central Park makes the park a child-friendly zone and avails the services that its visitors need. At one end of the Park is a Children’s playground with a wide range of facilities for Children to play on such as swings and other playing materials. Central park has expansive lawns and well maintained gardens, interspersed with shade trees. It also has flowers which make the park attractive. Picnicking at this park is a favourite pastime with Nairobi residents on weekends and public holidays. Those seeking to find jobs in the city also find a resting place in this park in between their searches. People could also use this park as a meeting place, an advertising place through putting up tents which attract the people, and among many others ways. Central Park is easily accessible to residents of Nairobi from all corners of the city and it is open for free to the public in Kenya. There are toilet facilities provided in  Central Park in Kenya where the public use at a fee. The Nairobi City Council ensures that it maintains  Central Park and makes it as friendly as possible. In Nairobi, there are other similar parks which people could visit which include Jeevanjee Gardens, Nairobi Arboretum, Uhuru Gardens, Nairobi City Park and Uhuru Park.</string>
    <string name="tom_mboya_name">Tom Mboya Memorial Statue</string>
    <string name="tom_mboya_location">Moi Avenue</string>
    <string name="tom_mboya_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="tom_mboya_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="tom_mboya_about">The Tom Mboya Monument is along the Moi Avenue in Nairobi, Kenya. It was erected in 2011[1] in honour of Tom Mboya, a Kenyan minister who was assassinated in 1969. The monument stands about twenty meters from where Mboya was murdered. The statue stands at not less than ten meters from ground level. Since its unveiling, the monument\'s location has proven to be one of the most popular rendezvous currently available within the Nairobi CBD</string>
    <string name="peace_museum_name">Peace Memorial Museum</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_name">Nairobi Railway Museum</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_location">Station Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_contact">+254 724 380975</string>
    <string name="peace_museum_about">The Peace Memorial Museum was created and designed within the Visitors Centre to honor those who lost their lives during the tragic event on 7th August 1998. It was also developed to tell the stories of those who survived and for those whose lives were changed forever by the 1998 terrorist bombing of the US Embassy. The images and exhibits on display are meant to educate the public on the appalling consequences of terrorism and sensitize visitors on the need for peace, tolerance and reconciliation. By the end of the museum tour it is hoped that each person will be inspired to support peace.</string>
    <string name="railways_museum_about">Kenya Railways represents the historical growth of this country and Nairobi Railway Museum narrates the tale of this country’s evolvement; indeed it is the rail that developed Kenya to the country it is now! The Nairobi Railway Museum was opened in 1971, and much of the credit for its foundation goes to its first Curator, Mr. Fred Jordan, who had been with the railways in East Africa as from 1927. Realising the speed at which changes were taking place on the railway system he saw the need to preserve as many links with the past as possible. He began to gather items which were to form the nucleus of the present day museum’s fascinating and growing collection. The Nairobi Railway Museum provides answers to many unanswered questions concerning the early history of the rail and Kenya’s development. Nairobi Railway museum consists of the Main Gallery, the Resource Center, the auditorium and an outdoor collection of locomotives, wagons and coaches.</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_name">Nairobi National Park</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_location">Langata Road, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_opening">0600</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_closing">1900</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_contact">+254 20 602121</string>
    <string name="nairobi_national_park_about">A short drive out of Nairobi’s central business district is the Nairobi National Park. Wide open grass plains and backdrop of the city scrapers, scattered acacia bush play host to a wide variety of wildlife including the endangered black rhino, lions, leopards, cheetahs, hyenas, buffaloes, giraffes and diverse birdlife with over 400 species recorded. Visitors can enjoy the park’s picnic sites, three campsites and the walking trails for hikers.</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_name">Nairobi Safari Walk</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_location">Nairobi</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_closing">1730</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_contact">+254 20 2379407</string>
    <string name="nairobi_safari_walk_about">With its raised wooden boardwalk that allows for uninterrupted views of the animals, the Safari Walk is a show case for Kenya’s Parks and Reserves, allowing visitors to discover what they can expect to see across the country. Visitors can see a sample of the country’s rich animal life including the rare bongo, white rhino and albino zebra as well as big cats, antelopes and primates. It is also home to some 150 species of local trees.</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_name">Nairobi Animal Orphanage</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_location">Nairobi</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_contact">0800 597 000</string>
    <string name="animal_orphanage_about">The Nairobi Animal Orphanage is located in the Nairobi National Park. It serves a treatments and rehabilitation centre for wild animals. The Orphanage hosts lions, cheetahs, hyenas, jackals, serval cats, rare Sokoke cats, warthogs, leopards, various monkeys, baboons and buffalo. Various birds can also be viewed including parrots, guinea fowls, crowned cranes and ostriches.</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_name">Giraffe Centre</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_location">Duma Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_contact">+254 20 8070804</string>
    <string name="giraffe_center_about">The Africa Fund for Endangered Wildlife (A.F.E.W.) Kenya was founded in 1979 by the late Jock Leslie-Melville, a Kenyan citizen of British descent, and his American-born wife, Betty Leslie-Melville. They began the Giraffe Centre after discovering the sad plight of the Rothschild Giraffe. A subspecies of the giraffe found only in the grasslands of East Africa. The Giraffe Centre has also become world-famous as a Nature Education Centre, educating thousands of Kenyan school children every year At the time, the animals had lost their habitat in Western Kenya, with only 130 of them left on the 18,000-acre Soy Ranch that was being sub-divided to resettle squatters. Their first effort to save the subspecies was to bring two young giraffes, Daisy and Marlon, to their home in the Lang’ata suburb, southwest of Nairobi. Here they raised the calves and started a programme of breeding giraffe in captivity. This is where the centre remains to date. Betty and Jock then registered A.F.E.W. in the United States. Funds were raised to move five other groups of giraffe to different safe areas. Breeding herds of 26 giraffes were translocated from Soy Ranch to the Ruma Game Reserve in present-day Homa Bay County, Lake Nakuru National Park in Nakuru and Nasolot Game Reserve in modern-day West Pokot County. In 1985, seven giraffes were introduced to Yodder Flower Farm near the Mwea Game Reserve in Mbeere District in Eastern Kenya. In 1983, funds raised by A.F.E.W. USA helped build the Educational Centre on a 60-acre sanctuary. This with the extraordinary vision of creating an educational institution in conjunction with rescuing the giraffe. The Giraffe Centre opened its doors to the general public and students the same year, receiving over 800 excited students. There are now over 300 Rothschild Giraffe safe and breeding well in various Kenyan national parks. Recent herds have been introduced to Soysambu Ranch by Lake Elementaita in the Great Rift Valley, Kigio Conservancy and the Sergoit Ranch in the Mount Elgon region.</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_name">The David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_location">KWS Central Workshop Gate</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_opening">1100</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_closing">1200</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_contact">+254 (0) 202 301 396</string>
    <string name="david_sheldrick_about">Born from one family’s passion for Kenya and its wilderness, the David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust is today the most successful orphan-elephant rescue and rehabilitation program in the world and one of the pioneering conservation organisations for wildlife and habitat protection in East Africa. Founded in 1977 by Dr Dame Daphne Sheldrick D.B.E, in honour of the memory of her late husband, famous naturalist and founding Warden of Tsavo East National Park, David Leslie William Sheldrick MBE, the DSWT claims a rich and deeply rooted family history in wildlife and conservation. The DSWT has remained true to its principles and ideals, remaining a sustainable and flexible organisation. Guided by experienced and dedicated Trustees and assisted by an Advisory Committee of proactive naturalists with a lifetime of wildlife and environmental experience, the Trust takes effective action and achieves long-lasting results. The David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust embraces all measures that compliment the conservation, preservation and protection of wildlife. These include anti-poaching, safe guarding the natural environment, enhancing community awareness, addressing animal welfare issues, providing veterinary assistance to animals in need, rescuing and hand rearing elephant and rhino orphans, along with other species that can ultimately enjoy a quality of life in wild terms when grown. Chaired by Daphne Sheldrick, the DSWT is run by Angela Sheldrick, the daughter of David and Daphne, who has been managing all of the Trust’s activities for over a decade. Growing up in Tsavo and later in the Nairobi National Park, Angela has been part of the Trust’s vision from the start, supported by her husband Robert Carr-Hartley and their two boys Taru and Roan, who are passionate about Kenya’s wildlife and eager to ensure that David and Daphne’s legacy continues. In 2004 the DSWT was incorporated as a charity in the U.K. and granted charitable status by the Charities Commission, whilst during the same year the Trust has also attained U.S. Charitable status enhancing its corporate funding capability under the guidance of the U.S. Friends of the David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust. Helping save the lives of orphaned elephants and rhinos through the ‘Orphans’ Project’ who are ultimately released back into the wild is just one of the many wildlife commitments the David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust is involved in. The DSWT also runs 9 full-time Anti-Poaching and Desnaring Units, 4 Mobile Veterinary Units and the Sky Vets initiative, 5 ‘Aerial Surveillance’ planes and a rapid response helicopter, whilst being active in ‘Saving Habitats’, ‘Conservation Initiatives’ and ‘Community Outreach’.</string>
    <string name="oloolua_name">Oloolua Nature Trail</string>
    <string name="oloolua_location">Karen Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="oloolua_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="oloolua_closing">1800</string>
    <string name="oloolua_contact">38825714</string>
    <string name="oloolua_about">The Oloolua Nature Trail is a favourite with visitors coming to do a short hike, to jog along the trail, to walk their dogs, or just for a relaxing picnic in this serene setting. Organized groups also come to learn about environmental conservation through guided tours in the forest. The Oloolua nature trail meanders through thick forest vines and undergrowth below giant indigenous trees and bushes, in some places following the course of the Mbagathi River that cuts through the forest. Giant riverside bamboo stands beckon you to descend some rickety stairs to the river and rest on benches built under the bamboo. Trickling water and chirping birds, the only sounds you hear as you rest, lull you into a reflective mood. Further along the trail close to the river, you encounter a 33m long cave. If you brought a flashlight with you, an exploration of this dark subterranean world takes you through numerous underground caverns reputed to have once been home to Mau Mau freedom fighters during the colonial period of Kenya’s History. A thick pile of guano underfoot and the occasional disturbance of bats flitting past you bring to your attention the existence of a bat colony within. A papyrus swamp further down the river offers a further glimpse into the rich biodiversity of this indigenous forest. From here on, the trail climbs out of the river valley, occasional bursting upon glades bathed in bright sunlight before diving back under the canopy of the cool forest cover. A picnic site complete with benches, drop toilets and trash bins offers a nice setting for couples or groups to rest, play or enjoy a meal within the forest. For those wishing to spend more than a day in the forest, a secure campsite is also available complete with tap water, drop toilets, and firewood for lighting a bonfire. You’ll have to bring your own tent, food and cooking utensils though. Last and perhaps the most spectacular of the attractions in the forest is a 20-foot waterfall close to the forest entrance. As you pick your way along the trail to the waterfall, you’ll go past a wooden tower that was constructed some years back for viewing a Crowned Eagle’s nest that was situated nearby.  Scientists used this tower to study the Crowned Eagle’s behaviour in its natural habitat. Sadly, human activities and settlements close to the forest have resulted in the birds migrating from this haven.</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_name">Karen Blixen Museum</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_location">Karen Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_opening">0830</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_closing">1730</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_contact">020 8002139</string>
    <string name="karen_blixen_about">Karen Blixen Museum was once the centre piece of a farm at the foot of the Ngong Hills owned by Danish Author Karen and her Swedish Husband, Baron Bror von Blixen Fincke. Located 10km from the city centre, the Museum belongs to a different time period in the history of Kenya. The farm house gained international fame with the release of the movie ‘Out of Africa’ an Oscar winning film based on Karen’s an autobiography by the same title. The Museum is open to the Public every day (9.30 am to 6pm) including weekends and public holidays. Visitors are encouraged to be at the Museum by 5.30.  Guided tours are offered continuously.  A museum shop offers handicrafts, posters and postcards, the Movie ‘Out of Africa’, books and other Kenyan souvenirs. The grounds may be rented for wedding receptions, corporate functions and other events. The Museum was built in 1912 by Swedish Engineer Ake Sjogren. Karen and her husband bought the Museum house in 1917 and it become the farm house for their 4500 acre farm, of which 600 acres was used for coffee farming. Their marriage failed after eight years and in 1921 the Baron moved on and left the running of the farm to Karen. Karen lived at the house until her return to Denmark in 1931. The house farm was bought by Remy Marin, who broke the land into 20 acre parcels for development. Subsequent development created the present suburb of Karen. Records indicate that a Lt. Col.G. Lloyd, an officer of the British Army bought the house in 1935 and lived there until his death in 1954, when it passed to his daughters, Mrs. G. Robersts and Lavender Llyod.  A transfer of title to Mrs. J.P Robson and Mrs L.B. Hyde is in City Hall records in 1956.  The house was sporadically occupied until purchased in 1964 by the Danish government and given to the Kenyan government as an independence gift. The government set up a college of nutrition and the Museum was initially used as the principal’s house. In 1985 the shooting of a movie based on Karen’s autobiography began and the National Museums of Kenya expressed acquired the house for the purpose of establishing a Museum. The Museum was opened in 1986. Karen also known by her pen name Isak Dinesen was born at Rungstedlund in Denmark on 17th of April 1885 as the second child of Wilhelm and Ingeborg Dinesen’s five children. She came to Africa in 1914 to marry her half cousin and carry out dairy farming in the then British Colony of Kenya. Her husband had however changed his mind and wanted to farm coffee. Her uncle Aage Westenholz financed the farm and members of both families were share holders. The coffee farm did not do well, suffering various tragedies including factory fire and continuous bad harvest. After her divorce, Karen was left to run the financially troubled farm on her own, a daunting task for a woman of that generation. She fell in love with an English man, Denis Finch Hatton, and his death in Tsavo in 1930 coupled with the failed farming left Karen little choice but to return to Denmark. She turned to writing as a career following her departure from Africa and published to increasing acclaim such works as Seven Gothic Tales(1934) Out of Africa(1937) and Babette Feat (1950). She died on her family estate, Rungsted, in 1962 at the age of 77. Karen_blixen_museum Karen Blixen Museum The Karen Blixen house meets three of the customary criteria for historical significance. First, it is associated with the broad historical pattern of European settlement andcultivation of East Africa. Second, it is associated with the life of aperson significant to our past as the home of Baroness Karen Blixen from 1917 -1931. As such, it served as the setting and basis of herwell known book Out of Africa, written under the pseudonym Isak Dinesenand as a gathering place for other well known personalities of the period. Third, the building embodies the distinctive characteristicsof its type, period and method of construction. The house’s architecture is typical of late 19th century bungalow architecture,including the spacious rooms, horizontal layout verandas, tile roof and stone construction typical of scores of residences built throughout European suburbs of Nairobi in early decades. The chronology of the house begins with its construction in 1912 by the wealthy Swedish civil engineer, later honorary Swedish consul to Kenya, Ake Sjogren. It served as the main residence on his Swedo-African coffee company , an estate of over 6,000 acres. The house was soon visited while on safari by the Danish count Mojen Frijs, who upon his return to Denmark persuaded his cousin to seek their fortune in Kenya.Baron Blixen acquired part of the estate in 1913 and the remainder in 1916. Karen Blixen called the house “Bogani” or “Mbogani” meaning a house in the woods, and occupied it until 1931. By1985, with renewed interest in Karen Blixen occasioned by the film production of Out of Africa, an agreement was reach with the collage for the house to become part of the National Museums of Kenya. Many pieces of furniture that Karen Blixen sold to Lady McMillan on her departure were acquired back and constitute part of the exhibition in the Museum. The Museum house remains a serene environment that seems to belong to the past, surrounded by a tranquil garden and indigenous forest, with a splendid view of Karen’s beloved Ngong Hills. She honours the hills with the phrase ‘I had a farm in Africa at the foot of the Ngong Hills’.</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_name">Kazuri Beads Factory</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_location">Mbagathi Ridge, Karen</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_contact">+254 727 647206</string>
    <string name="kazuri_beads_about">Kazuri, which means “small and beautiful” in Swahili, began in 1975 as a tiny workshop experimenting in hand crafted ceramic beads. Its founder started with two single motherhood women and soon discovered that there were many others in the villages around Nairobi, most of who were disadvantaged and were in great need of regular employment. Today Kazuri has grown tremendously and now has a large workforce of over 340 women skilled in the crafting of ceramic beads, strung into beautifully and artistically jewelry. The flair has taken us to a different dimension of making our own unique range of pottery which reflects the culture and wildlife of Kenya. Each piece, like our beads, is handmade and hand painted in rich colors.</string>
    <string name="galleria_name">Galleria Mall</string>
    <string name="galleria_location"><![CDATA[Junction of Magadi &, Langata Rd, Nairobi]]></string>
    <string name="galleria_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="galleria_closing">2200</string>
    <string name="galleria_contact">020 2363063</string>
    <string name="galleria_about">If you are looking for a shopping experience that will truly surpass your expectations, a dining destination with such rich variety it leaves you totally spoilt for choice or a lifestyle experience that is fully enriching and rewarding, then look no further than Galleria Shopping Mall, the home of the unlimited experience. Picture this; a breathtaking edifice with 3 floors of shopping, dining, and other lifestyle services standing on 12 acres of land, 550 parking bays, 250 capacity Food Zone and a  vibrant children\'s play area, these and much more designed to give you a stress free, convenient, fun, and entertaining experience. Originally designed to cater for the unmet need of the Karengat area by providing a wide selection of stores with a variety of products and services, Galleria Shopping Mall now stands on a class of its own as a vibrant modern shopping, dining and entertainment destination serving the Karen, Langata, Rongai, Ngong, Nairobi West, South B as well as the rest of Nairobi City residents. In many ways, shopping at Galleria leaves you with a feeling of the great outdoors, a tribute to its unique architecture creatively designed unlike the ‘big box’ model with lots of wide open spaces to let in the beautiful African weather. The mall is also adorned with a warm colour scheme to capture and reflect the Kenyan red earth and the African sunset.</string>
    <string name="bomas_name">Bomas of Kenya</string>
    <string name="bomas_location">Langata Rd</string>
    <string name="bomas_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="bomas_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="bomas_contact">+254 20 8891012</string>
    <string name="bomas_about">Bomas of Kenya offers Kenya in miniature! It is a must visit to all visitors. Situated 10km from Nairobi city center, and about 1 km past main entrance of the game-filled Nairobi National Park, Bomas of Kenya lets you see the wonderful diversity of cultures that make up this fascinating country. At Bomas different aspects of Kenyan culture are displayed including living styles, crafts, music and dancing. The word Bomas was derived from \"Boma\"-a Swahili word for enclosed homestead and there are now many different \"Bomas\", each one representing one of Kenya\'s major ethnic groups. You, cannot afford to miss the most exciting traditional dances and acrobatic show which starts at 2.30pm to 4.00pm during A weekdays and 3.30pm to 5.15pm weekends and public holidays.</string>
    <string name="jeevanjee_name">Jeevanjee Gardens</string>
    <string name="jeevanjee_location">Biashara Street and Moi Avenue, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="jeevanjee_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="jeevanjee_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="jeevanjee_about">Jeevanjee Gardens is an open garden in the Central Business District of Nairobi, Kenya. Jeevanjee Gardens was founded by A.M. Jeevanjee, an Asian-born entrepreneur in Kenya.[1] It is the only park in the city that is directly owned by the people, having been donated to the poor people of Nairobi as a resting area (the park was private property and it is held in trust for the people of Nairobi).</string>
    <string name="stedmak_name">StedMak Gardens</string>
    <string name="stedmak_location">Mokoyeti Rd E, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="stedmak_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="stedmak_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="stedmak_contact">0705 734780</string>
    <string name="stedmak_about">StedMak Gardens has gained a reputation for being one of the most esteemed event spaces in Karen. We pride ourselves on offering the perfect venue for creating memorable events, casual or formal, small or large. Situated away from the City center of Nairobi. StedMak Gardens was established in (2000). Visiting the Gardens one samples  the culture and history of two counties, that is Nairobi and Kajiado. The influence of the city dwellers and Maasai, culture and history is everywhere. The customs have evolved as much from its native environment to the mixture of cultures that have now settled here.</string>
    <string name="museum_name">Nairobi National Museum</string>
    <string name="museum_location">Museum Hill, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="museum_opening">0830</string>
    <string name="museum_closing">1730</string>
    <string name="museum_contact">020 3742131</string>
    <string name="museum_about">The Museum aims to interpret Kenya’s rich heritage and offers a one stop for visitors to sample the country’s rich heritage both for education and leisure. In addition to the museum, visitors are treated to a variety of shopping and dining facilities, as well as botanical gardens that offer a serene environment.  The museum is open on all 356 days throughout the year from 0830hrs -17300hrs.Nairobi National Museum is located at the Museum Hill, approximately 10 minutes drive from the Nairobi city centre accessible both by public and private means. Built in 1929, this is the flagship museum for the National Museums of Kenya, housing celebrated collections of Kenya’s History, Nature, Culture and Contemporary Art. The Museum was initiated in 1910 by a group of enthusiastic naturalists under the then East Africa and Uganda Natural History Society [currently the East African Natural History Society (EANHS)], who needed a place to keep and preserve their collections of various specimens. The first site for the museum was at the present Nyayo House, which later became too small and a larger building was put up in 1922 where the Nairobi Serena Hotel stands today. In 1929, the colonial government set aside land for a museum construction at Museum Hill which was officially opened in September 22nd 1930 and named Coryndon Museum in honour of Sir Robert Coryndon, one time Governor of Kenya. In 1963 after independence, it was re-named the National Museum of Kenya (NMK). On October 15th 2005, the Nairobi Museum closed its doors to the public for an extensive modernization and expansion project the outcome of which was an impresive and magnificent piece of architecture that puts it in competition with other world- class museums. The museum later re-opened in June 2008 as the Nairobi National Museum, and continues to draw visitors from all walks of life in appreciation of Kenya’s rich heritage. The artworks and materials used in the fabrication of outdoor sculptures, the landscaping and the botanic gardens, link to the four pillars of Kenya’s national heritage i.e. nature, culture, history and contemporary art. In addition to offering visitor’s with Kenya’s rich heritage, the museum is also well known as a unique events venue, for the appreciation of Kenya’s heritage amidst workshops, cocktails, conferences and other functions. For more information visit</string>
    <string name="hilton_name">Hilton Nairobi</string>
    <string name="hilton_location">Mama Ngina St, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="hilton_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="hilton_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="hilton_contact">+254–20-2288000</string>
    <string name="hilton_about">Hilton Nairobi is a landmark hotel offering the ideal space for work and leisure. Our hotel offers modern facilities for business and relaxation. Organize meetings in any of our 11 spacious conference rooms. Book a stay in our high rise tower rooms with magnificent city views. Relax with our amenities including a health club and heated outdoor pool. We are near Nairobi’s top attractions, including the maasai market and the city’s historic landmarks.</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_name">Sarova Stanley</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_location">Junction Of Kenyatta Avenue and Kimathi Street</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_contact">0709 111000</string>
    <string name="sarova_stanley_about"><![CDATA[Sarova Stanley is amongst the few five star rated hotels in Nairobi. It launched itself into Kenyan history in 1902 by becoming the first luxury hotel in Nairobi and the gracious host to prominent world leaders, renowned authors, and international celebrities. Sarova Stanley retains much of its historical charm while at the same time offering all the luxuries and amenities of a five-star hotel. Today, Sarova Stanley\'s heritage character is preserved whilst offering modern hotel services and amenities to create Nairobi\'s best hotel experience. The hotel is also a member of Preferred Hotels & Resorts, in the Lifestyle Collection. If you crave to enjoy the luxurious amenities provided by the best 5-star hotels in Kenya or taste world-class cuisines, then booking an accommodation here lets you achieve it.]]></string>
    <string name="norfolk_name">Fairmont The Norfolk Hotel</string>
    <string name="norfolk_location">Harry Thuku Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="norfolk_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="norfolk_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="norfolk_contact">020 2265000</string>
    <string name="norfolk_about">A beloved landmark dating back to 1904, Fairmont The Norfolk has played a pivotal role in Kenya’s historical legacy notably as the town and later the modern city of Nairobi grew around the property. A hidden gem with alluring old-world charm and elegant contemporary design, Fairmont The Norfolk offers guests a sophisticated retreat in the city with easy access to key business districts of Gigiri, Westlands and Upperhill in addition to leisure hubs and the bourgeoning Nairobi art scene. The hotel boasts of 27 luxurious suites and 143 rooms set around tranquil tropical gardens, a heated outdoor swimming pool and a health club with a fitness centre and indulgent spa facilities. The rooms combine classic elegance and modern design with discreet technology. Many rooms offer breathtaking elevated views of the landscaped courtyard, while the signature suites are an excellent choice for guests seeking to experience luxury intertwined with the rich history of the city. For over a century business has been discussed and deals struck on the verandah of this iconic heritage hotel. The tradition continues as The Norfolk remains the ideal meetings and events venue, now with 8 distinctive spaces able to accommodate up to 200 delegates. The venue is ideal for an executive board meeting, large convention, corporate dinner or casual business breakfast and lunch in the restaurant. Elegant spaces are also available for intimate celebrations and lavish soirees. Fairmont The Norfolk offers superb dining options with local produce, authentic flavors and varied choices on the menu including organically sourced beef, fresh sea food and vegan dishes. The award-winning Tatu restaurant offers warm and attentive service in a contemporary African themed setting while The Lord Delamere Terrace, once Nairobi’s most famous meeting place, retains all its classic charm as an all-day dining restaurant serving one of the best breakfast buffets in the city. An elegant lounge bar overlooking the garden; Cin Cin welcomes guests to sip on signature cocktails and discover the extensive array of wines, whiskies and premium alcoholic beverages alongside the exquisite tapas menu and T Lounge offers the perfect spot for afternoon tea accompanied by traditional delights. Whether at the start or end of a Kenyan safari adventure, or passing through on business, Fairmont The Norfolk, 18 km drive from the Jomo Kenyatta international airport is a peaceful haven for all guests.</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_name">Nairobi Gallery</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_location">Kenyatta Ave, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_opening">0830</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_closing">1730</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_contact">020 3742131</string>
    <string name="nairobi_gallery_about">Located at the intersection of Kenyatta Avenue/ Uhuru Highway in the heart of Nairobi City is the Nairobi Gallery. Built in 1913, this was the Old PC’s office building fondly referred to as ‘Hatches, Matches and Dispatches’ because of the births, marriages and deaths that were recorded here. Today, the building is a National Monument and serves as a museum holding temporary art exhibitions.</string>
    <string name="godown_name">Go-Down Arts Centre</string>
    <string name="godown_location">Dunga Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="godown_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="godown_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="godown_contact">0726 992200</string>
    <string name="godown_about">The GoDown Arts Centre is home to Kenyan creativity in arts and media. Established in 2003, in a space that was formerly a car repair warehouse, the centre has contributed significantly to the growth, recognition and visibility of local artist by fostering and facilitating collaborations and encounters between artists from different disciplines and different parts of the world.</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_name">Circle Art Gallery</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_location">James Gichuru Road, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_opening">1000</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_closing">1700</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_contact">0790 289991</string>
    <string name="circle_art_gallery_about">Founded in 2012, and based in Nairobi, Kenya, Circle Art Gallery promotes contemporary art from Eastern Africa. Through group and solo exhibitions, as well as participation in various international art fairs, the gallery has increased local and international visibility for established and emerging artists. Working closely with local and international collectors and curators, we are building a strong and sustainable market for East African artists.</string>
    <string name="snake_park_name">Nairobi Snake Park</string>
    <string name="snake_park_location">Museum Hill Centre, Muthithi Rd, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="snake_park_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="snake_park_closing">1730</string>
    <string name="snake_park_contact">020 8164134</string>
    <string name="snake_park_about">The Nairobi Snake Park was started in January, 1961 to meet a popular attraction and to provide a research facility on reptiles, breeding of snakes. Live snakes were exhibited on experimental basis at the entrance of the Museum in 1958 which later became a popular attraction.When the popularity was noted, a portion of land in front of the Museum and down to the Nairobi River was acquired by the Museum Trustees for the development of Botanical gardens and exhibitions on live snakes. This idea was developed further in 1959, when money was made available for a combined facility, Snake Park and Snake study centre surrounded by a botanical garden and war memorial garden on one end. By the end of 1960, the Snake Park was almost completed using funds made available by the War Memorial Committee. The Snake Park was opened to the public in January 1961, as a centre for snake study before it transformed into a shelter for resqued reptiles and amphibians. It attracted a lot of interest from the public, researchers, conservationist and educators. Following its closure in August 2008, the snake park reopened a year later after undergoing a major lift. During the 2009/2010 financial year, about 123,000 visitors attended the park. In a bid to serve our visitors better, public programmes like octopus exhibition, interactive sessions with harmless reptiles and amphibians, exhibition on the birds of the Snake Park and feeding of crocodiles with live fish. Audio Visual transmission of information on exhibitions, are under way. The aquaria have been modified with a classy touch of beautiful art work for their finishing. It is your world class tourist destination! Currently the Snake Park exhibits major groups,Invertebrates like Giant Snails, Baboon Spider ,Mombasa Train Millipede, Crayfish, Freshwater Prawns and Vertebrates like Fishes both Marine and Fresh water, Amphibians, Reptiles, Birds and Mammals. It is also offering services such as rescue and rehabilitation centre for reptiles (abandoned, confiscated, illegal collection), dissemination of information on aquarium fishes and reptiles as well as specialized talks on the same. To date, Snake Park has continued assisting the city residents of Nairobi in rescuing their residential areas by removing spotted house snakes and as well as giving advices on how to reduce possible snakebites within their homesteads. Snake identification service is also provided.</string>
    <string name="kuona_name">Kuona Artists collective, Centre for the Visual Arts</string>
    <string name="kuona_location">Likoni Cl, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="kuona_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="kuona_closing">2000</string>
    <string name="kuona_contact">0733 742752</string>
    <string name="kuona_about">Kuona Trust is a not-for-profit organisation founded in 1995 at the National Museum of Kenya to serve visual artists and has since worked with over one thousand five hundred artists giving them skills and opportunities to advance themselves while increasing the profile and role of the visual arts in Kenya.Kuona later moved to the GoDOWN Art Centre and in late 2008, Kuona Trust moved from the GoDown to a new premises of about 2 ½ acres of land located off Dennis Pritt Road in the Kilimani area of Nairobi, where we are currently based. Kuona has been in the forefront of developing the visual art scene in Kenya in the last 17 years with at least 1,000 artists participating in Kuona programmes. Kuona’s mentors artists giving them skills and opportunities to advance themselves whilst increasing the profile and role of visual arts in Kenya. Kuona provides support and resources to artists to make the great art of our day.</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_name">African Heritage House</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_location">Mombasa Road</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_closing">1800</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_contact">0721 518389</string>
    <string name="african_heritage_about">My name is Alan Donovan. I came to Africa over 50 years ago and was, together with Kenya’s first vice-president Joseph Murumbi, the co-founder of the African Heritage Gallery and the creator of the African Heritage House. African Heritage House is a showpiece of African culture and heritage and contains an invaluable collection of African art. Overlooking the Nairobi National Park, it is a combination of the mud architectures from across Africa and is available for tours, meals (breakfast, lunch, and dinners on the rooftop or by the refreshing pool), conferences/functions, as well as overnight stays in its luxurious rooms, filled with African art and furnishings with modern appointments.</string>
    <string name="laico_name">Laico Regency Hotel</string>
    <string name="laico_location">Uhuru Hwy, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="laico_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="laico_closig">0000</string>
    <string name="laico_contact">020 2211199</string>
    <string name="laico_about">Featuring a casino, Laico offers spacious rooms with an elegant décor in the centre of Nairobi. It also includes a spa, shopping arcade, and 5 restaurants. Free WiFi and parking is available on site. The air-conditioned rooms have views of the park or city centre. All include a TV with satellite channels and a bathroom stocked with bathrobes and free toiletries. Some rooms have a separate seating area. Guests can enjoy freshly baked pastries at the Royal Terrace Coffee Shop. There is a pool bar, which offers a barbecue buffet and live entertainment on Sundays. Laico Regency has a heated outdoor pool with a sun-lounger terrace. Guests can schedule a variety of beauty treatments at the spa. Nairobi national Park is 10 km from Laico Regency Hotel. Jomo Kenyatta International Airport is 15 km away, and a shuttle is available on request.</string>
    <string name="serena_name">Nairobi Serena Hotel</string>
    <string name="serena_location">Processional Way, Nairobi City</string>
    <string name="serena_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="serena_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="serena_contact">020 2822000</string>
    <string name="serena_about">Beyond the bustle of Kenya’s most cosmopolitan metropolis, experience a haven of elegance and calm nestled among lush gardens at the edge of Nairobi’s Central Park. Our Nairobi hotel merges business and leisure, art and gastronomy and five-star style and service. Nairobi Serena Hotel is a celebration of sophistication and a rich fusion of design influences from Ethiopia, the Maghreb, West Africa and East Africa. The warmth of a friendly smile, a superlative eye for detail and gracious service at our Nairobi hotel envelop you from the moment you arrive. While the Nairobi skyline glitters just beyond your windows and the Central Business District is just a stroll away, you’ll feel worlds removed from urban distractions in this peaceful setting. As an affiliated member of the Leading Hotels of the World, we provide distinctive opportunities for you to find your own inspiration as you explore the city in search of new experiences. The manner in which we welcome you, exceed your every expectation during your stay and remember you upon your return is the essence of Nairobi Serena Hotel.</string>
    <string name="all_saints_name">All Saints Cathedral Nairobi</string>
    <string name="all_saints_location">Nairobi</string>
    <string name="all_saints_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="all_saints_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="all_saints_contact">020 2710702</string>
    <string name="all_saints_about">DR. Johann Ludwig Krapf, a German Lutheran, sent by the Church Missionary Society (CMS) arrived in Mombasa in the year 1844. Dr. Krapf established a mission station at Rabai some 15 miles inland.The Rt. Rev. William G. Peel, the first Bishop of the Diocese of Mombasa arrived in Nairobi at the same time as the uganda railway in 1900. He conducted the first Anglican service in Nairobi attended by the railway officials of East Africa. Two years later (1902) the first European Chaplain, the Rev. P.A. Bennet arrived to serve the growing European community in Nairobi and the surrounding areas. The Foundation Stone of the first St. Stephen’s Church built of wood and corrugated iron was laid by Bishop Peel in December 1903 and the Church was consecrated in 1904; it stood near where Parliament buildings now stand. This church was moved to Pumwani in 1922 and re-dedicated to St. John. Another St. Stephen’s was built of stone next to the first St. Stephen’s where the present Chamber of Parliament is now. It was demolished to make way for the extensions to Parliament in 1963. Because it was so strongly built dynamite had to be used to bring it down. The need for a larger church was realized and under the Revd. W.M Falloon money was steadily collected. During this time the original church of St. Mark’s Parklands was built in 1907. This was behind the present Parklands Police station. In July 1914 a public meeting of European Anglicans was held to raise money for a permanent church in the centre of Nairobi and the Foundation Stone for the Church of All Saints was laid on 3rd February 1917. On 31st July 1918, the newly appointed Bishop Heywood dedicated the incomplete new Church. (The first part of the Nave) The design of Mr. Temple Moore, an architect who ‘thought Gothic’ and was said to be one of the most outstanding architects in that style in the late Victorian era, was for a large church, and further portions of the building were completed in 1924, 1934 and in 1952 to a new design for the Chancel. In November 1924, the Church of All Saints became the Cathedral of the Highlands, equal in status to the Cathedral in Mombasa. However, even by 1934, the building had only progressed as far as the Chancel arch and it remained in that incomplete state until after the Second World War. In 1949 an appeal was launched to complete the building and the present building, All Saints Cathedral, was consecrated to the glory of God on 21st March 1952 by Bishop R. P. Crabbe.</string>
    <string name="arboretum_name">Nairobi Arboretum</string>
    <string name="arboretum_location">Nairobi</string>
    <string name="arboretum_opening">0600</string>
    <string name="arboretum_closing">1815</string>
    <string name="arboretum_contact">0733 823 045</string>
    <string name="arboretum_about">Nairobi Arboretum occupies 30.4 hectares and is situated 3 km from the city centre. It was established in 1907 by Mr. Battiscombe, Deputy Conservator of forests mainly as a site for exotic tree species trials. This was because foresters in Kenya had become concerned that indigenous trees that the railway relied on were getting depleted faster than they could regenerate. To add to the tree species, Mr. H.M. Gardner (Chief Conservators of Forests) also collect indigenous shrubs and trees that were introduced there each year in spite of drought and diseases. Arboretum Forest Station was gazetted as protected Forest Reserves in 1932 and is managed by Kenya Forest Service (KFS).  Nairobi Arboretum now hosts over 300 species of exotic and indigenous tree species. The arboretum also has over 100 species of migrant and resident bird species in addition to Sykes and Vervet monkeys.  Mammals: Monkeys – Vervet Monkeys or Black- faced guenon (Cercopithecus aethiops), Sykes or Blue Monkey (Cercopithecus mitis), Kenya Mole rat (Tachyoryctes ibeanus), four- toed hedgehog (Erinaceus albiventris), greater galago, fruit bats, mongooses and squirrels. Reptiles: Jackson’s three- horned chameleon (Chamaeleo jacksoni), High-casqued chameleon (Chamaeleo hoehneli), striped skink (Mabuya striata). Birds: African paradise flycatcher (Terpsiphone viridis), White-eyed slaty flycatcher (Melaenornis fischeri), Common bulbul (Pycnonotus barbatus), Malachite kingfisher (Alcedo cristata), African pied wagtail (Motacilla aguimp), Common fiscal (Lanius collaris), Black kite (Milvus migrans), Pied crow (Corvus albus), Hadada ibis (Bostrychia hagedash), Bronze mannikin (Lonchura cucullata), Bronze sunbird (Nectarina kilimensis), Baglafecht weaver (Ploceus baglafecht), Speckled mousebird (Colius striatus), Silvery- cheeked hornbill (Bycanistes brevis). Butterflies: Green- banded swallowtail (Papilio phorcas), Mother-of-pearl (Salamis’ parhassus), African emigrant (Catopsilia florella), Green- veined, White-barred, Black-bordered and Blue spotted charaxes, Diadem (Hypolimnas missipus). Indigenous trees: Croton megalocarpus, Brachylaena huillensis, Podocarpus falcatus, Markhamia lutea, Vepris simplicifolia, African Olive, Schebera alata, Craibia brownie, Erythrina abyssinica, Trichilia emetic, Gardenia ternifolia, Millettia dura, Adansonia digitata, Encephalartos hildebrandtii, Tamarindus indica, Monodora myristica, Spathodea campanulata, Canthium keniense, Premna maxima, Croton alienus, Catha edulis, Zanthoxylum gillettii, Brachylaena huillensis, Prunus Africana, East African yellow-wood, Newtonia buchananii, Vitex keniensis, Khaya anthotheca, Sweitenia mahogoni. Exotic trees: Araucaria columnaris, Araucaria cunninghamii, Araucaria bidwillii, Lagunaria pattersonii, Brachychiton acerifolium, Senna brewsteri, Castanospermum austral, Melaleuca styphelioides, Eucalyptus callitris, Grevillea , Casaurina, Eucalyptus paniculata, Eucalyptus maculate, Jacaranda mimosfolia, Tipuana tipu Schizolobium parahybum, Phytolacca dioica,Tabebuia chrysantha (yellow poui), Erythrina corallodendron, Erythrina velutina, Eucalyptus deglupta(Mindanao gum), Eriobotrya japonica, Ficus elastic, Ligustrum ovalifolium, Ficus benjamina, Ficus religiosa, Cupressus cashmeriana, Acrocarpus franxinifolius, Bauhinia purpurea, Bauhinia petersiana, Schotia brachypetala, Erythrina lysistemon, Peltophorum africanum, Bolusanthus speciosus( African tree wisteria), Strelitzia Nicolai, Strelitzia regina(Birds of paradise), Ravenala madagascariensis (Traveller’s palm), Pinus patula (Mexican weeping pine), Phoenix reclinata (Wild date palm), Phoenix canariensis (Canary palms).</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_name">Uhuru Gardens</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_location">Langata road</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_opening">0800</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_closing">1900</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_contact">0722 893612</string>
    <string name="uhuru_gardens_about">Located along Langata road, 15 minutes drive from the city center, is Uhuru Gardens, Kenya’s largest Memorial Park. Uhuru is a swahili word meaning freedom. The gardens were officially declared a National Monument in 1966 because of their historical importance. Of importance to note is that it is Kenya’s birthplace. This is where the first Kenyan flag was first raised and thus marking the very first year of independence on the 12th December 1963. Within the garden are two monuments commemorating Kenya’s independence, and a Mugumo (fig) tree. The Mugumo tree is symbolic as it was planted on the spot where the Union Jack (British flag) was brought down and Kenya’s national flag was first hoisted. The site was a diversity of native flora and fauna of savannah woodland. In addition to the historical significance, Uhuru Gardens continues to attract various events as a recreational park. It is popular as a rest area for families and friends, a must visit for schools and in recent times has gained popularity as an events venue for corporate launches, concerts, weddings, film location just to name a few. For those who are looking for a secure jogging spot, this is the perfect location for keeping fit. Future plans will include improving the park to have a wider variety of leisure activities for all. The Mashujaa/ heroes Corner will also be adjacent to this beautiful park which will mark as a reminder to celebrate our Kenyan heroes.</string>
    <string name="city_park_name">City Park</string>
    <string name="city_park_location">City Park Dr</string>
    <string name="city_park_opening">0000</string>
    <string name="city_park_closing">0000</string>
    <string name="city_park_about"><![CDATA[Tucked away on a portion of the Park is a public cemetery. This is the burial place of Pio Gama Pinto, a Journalist and Politician who actively participated in Kenya’s struggle for independence, only to be assassinated in 1965, barely two years after Independence. Adjacent to this cemetery is Murumbi Peace Memorial Park where <a href=\"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Murumbi\" target=\"_blank\">Joseph Murumbi</a>, Kenya&#8217;s second vice President, and his wife Sheila were buried. The Murumbis&#8217; legendary love for art and culture inspired a number of African artists to create the magnificent sculpture garden that is the Murumbi Memorial Park. Sadly, the grounds are neglected and overgrown with weeds, perhaps a testament to our indifference to our national heroes and the roles they played in our country’s history. The nature trails in Nairobi City Park are a favourite with nature lovers who come to get away from the city’s noise and congestion. Runners too love to jog on the Park’s trails. The open spaces in the Park get a lot of picnic lovers on weekends who often bring enough food to share with the troops of Sykes Monkeys milling around this area. Some hawkers operate in this area, armed with snacks and other items of interest to visitors. There is a bar and restaurant near the Nairobi County offices, providing a more conventional fare in this natural setting. Not to be missed is the magnificent sculpture garden whose pieces include the Bird of Peace by Elkana Ongesa, at the Murumbi Memorial Park.]]></string>
    <string name="kosewe_nam">K\'Osewe Ranalo Foods</string>
    <string name="kosewe_location">Kimathi Street</string>
    <string name="kosewe_opening">1030</string>
    <string name="kosewe_closing">0200</string>
    <string name="kosewe_contact">0721 323238</string>
    <string name="kosewe_about">A tale is told of a man, whose roots draw from the Lake-dwelling communities of Kenya. Osewe by name, the man grew up with the joy of enjoying freshly made fish recipes; secrets passed down from mothers to their sons and daughters. He caught Nairobi by storm, initially setting up a dingy hotel in the Eastlands of Nairobi. News of the sweet taste of his delicious fish recipes and sauces quickly spread across Nairobi, and he faced up to the task of satisfying the huge Nairobian appetite. The K’Osewe brand has grown and is currently the go-to restaurant in Nairobi. With ages of precision perfection, generations of secret skill and ingredients, K’Osewe gives you the best servings of organic whole foods south of the Sahara. Come savor the goodness of authentic continental dishes! Your day in Nairobi is only complete if you’ve had a meal at K’Osewe.</string>
    <string name="carnivore_name">Carnivore</string>
    <string name="carnivore_location">Lang\'ata Road</string>
    <string name="carnivore_opening">1130</string>
    <string name="carnivore_closing">2200</string>
    <string name="carnivore_contact">0733 611608</string>
    <string name="carnivore_about">The Carnivore is the ultimate \'Beast of a Feast\'  A variety of meats including ostrich, crocodile and camel, are roasted over charcoal and carved at your table. Delicious side dishes and an exceptional array of sauces complement this fixed price feast that also includes soup,a selection of desserts and Kenyan coffee. Set in attractive tropical gardens, the service and the décor are outstanding. The Carnivore opened its doors in September 1980 to instant success. The food, service and atmosphere were strikingly different from anything in Kenya and has since played host to over 2 million customers from across the globe including numerous celebrities. In fact the Carnivore visitors book read like a global who is who! The atmosphere combines the rustic feel of a rural setting and a medieval banquet hall. Another famous feature to set the tone of the Carnivore experience is the house cocktail The \'Dawa\' (magic potion in Swahili). It is based on a famous Brazilian drink, and was introduced to Kenyans at The Carnivore. It is brought to you on a portable tray by the medicine man fittingly named Dr. Dawa.</string>
    <string name="fogo_name">Fogo Gaucho</string>
    <string name="fogo_location">Groganville Estate Nairobi</string>
    <string name="fogo_opening">1200</string>
    <string name="fogo_closing">2230</string>
    <string name="fogo_contact">+254 712 123456</string>
    <string name="fogo_about">Over the last decade, Fogo Gaucho has established itself as one of Nairobi’s finest eateries. We are pleased to offer our patrons the choice of dining in our Westlands and Kilimani branches.  Fogo Gaucho is an authentic Brazilian Steakhouse that offers the most delectable selection of charcoal grilled meats that go along with a full buffet to choose from all for a set price per person, all you can eat. This concept in Brazil is referred to as Rodizio.  Our ambience is sure to give you the feeling that you are sitting in a Churrascaria (Steakhouse) right in the heart of Brazil as you enjoy a delicious meal for whatever occasion you are celebrating be it a birthday, anniversary, graduation, retirement, office party or just a special meal with your family and friends.  Once you enter and have a seat, our waiters will offer you a drink. You are then welcome to select what you like from the buffet where you will find a soup of the day, a variety of 20 fresh salads along with dressings and condiments, side dishes and hot dishes.   Once you are settled back at your table, our grill waiters will come around with a selection of 16 cuts of meat all prepared to perfection on the charcoal grill and you can select what you like and eat how much you like. The grill waiters will know if you would like meat because you will find a green/red token at your place setting on the table – turn it to green when you would like meat, and turn it to red if you would like to take a break or stop.  If you still have space for dessert, you can ask the waiters for our famous grilled pineapple with cinnamon sugar, and you can also visit the buffet again and take your pick from our offerings!  Welcome to Fogo Gaucho Churrascaria.</string>
    <string name="cjs_name">CJ\'s Restaurant</string>
    <string name="cjs_location">Koinange St, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="cjs_opening">0600</string>
    <string name="cjs_closing">2300</string>
    <string name="cjs_contact">0792 000090</string>
    <string name="cjs_about">Welcome to CJ’s, a fully fledged restaurant specializing in delivering a relaxed and memorable dining experience. We’re currently in 9 locations; 1 in Nairobi, 7 in Kampala and 1 in Entebbe. Each location features a unique ambience with tasteful décor, specially designed for your comfort. To make you feel more at home, we’ve carefully selected a unique theme for each location. We have over 300 carefully selected, mouthwatering menu items. Whatever your taste, it’s well catered for. We value you. That’s why you’ll always be served with excellence by each member of our highly skilled team members. Eager to serve you, our experienced wait staff greet you at the door and lead you to the table of your choice in the well thought out seating arrangement. The rich aroma of freshly ground coffee is the handiwork of our skilled baristas, adept in latte art. This ensures you get a freshly prepared cup of coffee as the beans are roasted on site. To ensure you always enjoy a special dining experience, we constantly improve our signature world-class innovations.</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_name">Kilimanjaro Jamia</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_location">Kimathi St, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_opening">0600</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_closing">2200</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_contact">0796 766808</string>
    <string name="kilimanjaro_about">The best restaurant to have a fine dinning with friends and family.  With  branches Situated  in  Nairobi.  We serve  the best  quality  meals  and ensure  we  use  the  best  of what  is  local  and sustainable. Our  restaurant  is  open   all day for relaxed dining in peaceful surroundings, perfect for that all-important business lunch. We   greatly   invite  you   to  visit  one  of our branches within Nairobi and enjoy delicious meals with friends and family.</string>
    <string name="hub_name">The Hub Karen Mall</string>
    <string name="hub_location">Nairobi</string>
    <string name="hub_opening">0900</string>
    <string name="hub_closing">2100</string>
    <string name="hub_contact">+254 702 120120</string>
    <string name="hub_about">The Hub Karen Mall is a premier shopping mall located in the beautiful leafy suburbs of Karen Nairobi catering to unique experiences and aims to trigger three of our five senses – Taste, Color and Sound all while placing importance on Real Estate in The Service of the Community. The HUB Karen is all about experience – The Hub is an environment where you can spend the whole day with all your needs being under one roof; from fashion, to entertainment, to fine dining and beyond. The Hub hosts both local and international retailers all while supporting small businesses. The Hub Karen has been developed over two phases, the first phase being a 35,000sqm gross area (excluding parking), featuring a retail, offices, medical, wellness centre which opened on February 4th 2016; phase 2 will include more parking and a hotel/conference centre. A skilled and experienced management company, Broll Property Group Kenya Ltd has been appointed to manage the complex with the mandate to achieve international standards.</string>
    <string name="village_market_name">The Village Market</string>
    <string name="village_market_location">Village Market, Nairobi</string>
    <string name="village_market_opening">0830</string>
    <string name="village_market_closing">2200</string>
    <string name="village_market_contact">020 7122488</string>
    <string name="village_market_about">The Village Market is East Africa’s largest Shopping, Recreation and Entertainment destination. The complex is home to over 150 outlets covering 210,000 square feet of retail space, 20,000 square feet of office space in addition to a recreation facility hosting a 12-lane bowling alley, Nu-Metro Cinema hall, 9 hi-tide waterslides among many other face. As the name suggests, the complex embodies the spirit of the African market in an open-air setting. To live up to its African theme, are waterfalls, rivers and over 2000 exotic plants and gardens, giving this magnificent shopping centre an edge over other shopping malls.</string>
    <string name="text_info">-</string>
    <string name="attraction_pager_info">Info</string>
    <string name="attraction_pager_about">About</string>
    <string name="open_24_hours">Open 24 hours</string>
    <string name="main_about">About</string>
    <string name="main_landmarks">Landmarks</string>
    <string name="main_museums">Museums&amp;Art</string>
    <string name="main_parks">Parks</string>
    <string name="main_restaurants">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="main_shopping">Shopping</string>
    <string name="main_wildlife">Wildlife</string>
    <string name="main_hotels">Hotels</string>
</resources>
